Hello friends, it occurs to me that I've
never actually put together a proper
tutorial for my skills repo. At the time
of recording this repo is up to 162,000
stars. We have 7.5 million downloads and
I've never made a tutorial for it. I get
questions all the time like what is the
sequence I should use these skills in,
how should I install them, how should I
set them up? So this video is going to
be a walk through of the main flow you
use when you're using these skills.
We're not going to look at the advanced
stuff, we're not going to look at the
new stuff really, we're just going to
focus on the main flow. The stuff you
need to get started. To walk you through
this, I'm going to be using one of my
work repos which is the AI Hero CLI.
This is the command line interface that
drives a lot of my exercises that I use
on my courses. I've never actually set
up my skills to work with this repo so
now is a great chance. If you want to
set up my skills on a brand new project,
you just do this except you do it in an
empty directory. So it works the same
whether you're using a brownfield code
base or a greenfield code base. I'm
going to open up the command line
interface here and I'm going to type NPX
skills at latest add mattpocock/skills.
This assumes a couple of things. It
assumes that you've got Node.js
installed. This NPX comes from Node.js
and it runs the skills.sh command line
installer from Vercel. What this
basically does is it installs a GitHub
repo of skills called mattpocockskills
and it can walk through a few setup
questions here. It first says it needs
to install the following packages. Yes,
that seems fine to me and then it did a
couple of things and we now have a long
long list of all the skills that we
could install. It found 38 skills here
which is a lot and you can see if I
scroll up and down that they're in two
groups. We've got the mattpocockskills
and then we've got other skills. So the
mattpocockskills are the ones that I
have blessed as the skills that I think
are good enough to be public facing. The
other ones are ones that I'm
experimenting with right now and may
delete in future. What I recommend you
do is you go to the top here and you can
kind of go up and down. It's kind of
broken, I have to say. And if you press
space here, and you should see that if
you scroll up, okay, they're now all
selected. You press space, and then you
press return, and now uh you've selected
all of the official skills. I'm not
terribly happy with Versel's CLI here,
so I may change it in future, or maybe
even just ship my own. But uh for now,
that's as good as it gets. One thing
that is good is that it will set up your
skills to work with any agent. So, I use
Claude Code, but you can go down here
and sort of just select the ones that
you want. I'm using space to select. I
think by default, if I zoom out a touch,
then it supports all of these universal
ones up here. So, cursor, Codex, Claude,
etc. But anything that uses like Claude
skills, such as Claude Code, then you
need to set up yourself. So, I'm going
to press return here, and it should now
be configured to set up my skills for
Claude Code. The installation scope
defines where your skills are installed,
whether they're installed just in the
current directory, or whether they're
global. This will depend on what your
team's conventions are. If you're
working in a team, I would say that
project skills are the right way to go.
That way, everyone is using the same
skill set on every project, and it means
that you can contribute to the skills
together and make those decisions
together. But global is fine if you're
just a solo developer working on your
own stuff, like I am. So, I'm going to
press return here, install it in my home
directory, and I'm going to choose
symlink as the recommended way. The
choice here is whether you copy it to
the agents folder as well as the dot uh
Claude folder. And
it's kind of not a nice way to do it.
Symlink is just the nice, easy way to do
it. So, I wouldn't even make a decision
here, just choose symlink. So, it now
gives you a summary of all the things
that you're installing here. There seems
to be an alert on Socket about to spec.
I'll take a look at that later. But yes,
we can proceed with installation, and
it's now installed all of the skills.
This means then that I can run Claude
inside here, or whatever your agent is,
and I'm going to create a new So, I'm
just going to say hello to get out of
this agent's view here. Now, depending
on the harness you're using, this will
show up in different ways, but on Cloud
Code, I can press forward slash and I
now see that I have a few skills
available to me. I have grill me,
grilling, way finder, grill with docs,
etc. Loads of stuff. Now, the difference
between my skills and lots of other
skills repos that are out there is my
skills are mostly user invoked. That
means that if I run context here, not
many of my skills actually leech their
way into the description. And the
descriptions I have are quite short and
precise. So, that means that even though
we've downloaded all of my skills, the
skills only take up 660 tokens here. So,
it's very, very light in terms of
context load. So, okay, we got the
skills. Now, what we have to do is we
have to run set up Mac Pocock skills.
And this will do a few things. My skills
rely on some uh configuration inside the
repository, and this does a few things
for you. The first thing is it means you
need to use an issue tracker. We're
going to be saving um specs, we're going
to be saving tickets, and we need to
save them somewhere. You've got kind of
an infinity of choices here. You can use
GitHub, you can use local markdown, or
you can literally use anything. The way
that the skill works is that it looks at
your local configuration. And so, you
can set it up for Jira, you can set it
up for Linear. And the way you do that
is you just tell the agent what you want
to set it up for, and it will go and set
it up for it. I just want to emphasize
that. People are asking me all the time,
"How do I make my skills work with Jira,
work with Beads, work with Linear?" It
already does. All you need to do is just
run set up Mac Pocock and just say, "Set
it up with Jira." Except, I don't want
to set it up with Jira. I'm just going
to set it up with local markdown,
please. So, that's fine by me. The next
question to answer here is about triage
labels. So, there are a set of labels
that the skill relies on to communicate
information about the tickets that it
produces. It's not really that important
here, so I'm just going to accept the
defaults. You can look at the docs on
the triage skill if you want to learn
more. So, defaults is fine. The next one
is about the domain documentation. So,
my skills like to have a little bit of
docs, a context .md file, and an ADR
inside the repo. And it's basically
asking if it's going to be a single
context or a multi-context. I think
single context is the way to go here.
Multi-context is if you have a big mono
repo and you need lots of different
bounded contexts within it. But for 99%
of people, a single context is going to
be fine. All right, so it's gone ahead
and written a few things here. The first
thing it's written is inside claw.md,
it's added a few little links here. So,
this is the new stuff. It's just linking
to the issue tracker docs, linking to
the triage labels, and linking to the
domain docs. And each of these are at
docs, agents, domain issue tracker. So,
we can see here that it's going to save
all of the issues and specs inside a
scratch file. So, with that, our setup
for this repo is complete. And so, you
might be thinking, how do I get started?
Well, before we get started, I'm going
to show you one more really cool thing.
You can, if you're following along, just
stop the video now and use one skill.
You can use the ask Matt skill. This ask
Matt skill is essentially me as a skill.
It knows everything that is needed about
the skills repo and what you should do
first. So, we can say, ask Matt, how do
I get started? I want to make some code
changes here. What is the main flow I
should use? I can now submit that and
see what it says. By the way, I'm using
Whisper flow as my transcription. So,
here we go. It's saying the main flow,
idea to ship. Since you have a code
base, start at the top of the main flow
and walk down in it in one unbroken
context window. So, it's very um
kind of really telling you how to use
your sessions as well. I I believe that
being conscious about the context window
that you're using, the tokens that
you're using is essential to using AI
well. It says you should start with
grill with docs. It interviews you to
sharpen the idea and because you're in a
repo it's stateful. It records what it
learns in context.md and ADRs. This is
where you turn I want to change X into a
crisp defensible plan. Defensible is
such an LLM phrase, honestly. Can you
settle every open question just by
talking? If a question needs a runnable
answer, then you can use prototype,
which I've done a video about on it.
Bridged in and out of by handoff, if not
skip this. Once you've done the
interview and grill with docs, you can
either go straight to the implement
skill, or if it needs multiple sessions
to go through, then you can go to to
spec and to tickets. Let me make this a
little bit clearer for you. The default
flow looks like this. You start with
grill with docs, and this interviews you
based on the idea that you want to
produce. For instance, if I clear out of
ask math, of course I could go and ask
follow-ups here, use it as a tutorial
itself, but let me just show you. I'm
going to say grill with docs, and I'm
going to kick it off with an idea. I'm
going to say, I would like to remove
most of the internal tooling on this CLI
to make it just only public-facing.
There's a lot of craft here. I want to
just take this repo down a notch. It
really can be as vague as this. You
don't need to do too much here. Grill
with docs is going to do the heavy
lifting by asking you a bunch of
follow-up questions. It's going and
exploring a bunch of code here. And by
the way, I'm [clears throat] using
Claude Code, I'm using Opus 4.8 on
medium effort, but you really don't have
to use the same setup as me. These
skills are being used by a bunch of
different people, bunch of different
harnesses, different models, different
effort levels. And we can see it's
already asked the first question here.
So, it's gotten a clear map of the
entire repo. It's looking at the
internal namespace with 11 subcommands.
So, this is what a grilling session
looks like. You go through all of the
questions until you feel or you and the
agent feel that you've reached a shared
understanding. I'm going to do that now,
and then I'll check in with you once I'm
done.
Okay, it didn't end up taking too long.
We ended up with what, six questions?
That's not very much for grilling
session. Usually mine end up being about
sort of 20 questions depending on the
size of it, but we've ended up with a
decent plan. We're going to delete uh 10
command files, delete three tests,
rewire shared modules. And all I did
here was I just answered questions until
it said, "Okay, we've walked the whole
tree. We've reached a shared
understanding. Let me lay out the plan."
Notice here, I wasn't using plan mode
for this. I was actually in auto mode in
claw code, which is kind of like the
default mode. And you now have a fork in
the road. If you think that this work is
going to be big enough that it will need
multiple agent sessions, then you can
skip numbers two and three here and go
straight into implement. The way you
would do that is you would just say, uh
forward slash implement this. And in
this case, I do think that is what we
should do. I've still got about, uh I
think of my context window is kind of
like ending or getting significantly
dumber around 140k
mark. I think of that as kind of like
the smart zone of the LLM. If you go
above 140k, you end up sort of with, you
know, attention degradation. It ends up
getting stupider, does weird
hallucinations. So, I think of having
like, okay, we've got 100k of budget
here to remove 10 commands. That seems
super easy. Definitely something, you
know, we can definitely do that. So,
this is what I would usually do. I would
just say implement and then I would
leave it, let it run, and it would
finish the work. However, in the
interest of showing you everything, I'm
going to pretend that this work is going
to take more than one session, that I've
maybe run out of context window in the
current or run out of smart zone in the
current window, and I'm going to need to
spread this out over multiple context
windows. So, I'm going to call to spec
here instead. So, instead of writing
implement this, I'm going to say to spec
here. And that's it. What this is going
to do is it's going to take all of the
discussion that I've had, all of this
46.1k tokens, and it's going to compress
it into a document that we can use
later. This is where our issue tracker
comes in. So, this issue tracker we're
just going to use local markdown files
and so it's just going to spit out the
spec into a local directory. This spec
is going to be the destination that
we're heading to over this multi-ticket
sprint. In other words, this is what
we're going to end up with. This is the
description of everything of how it's
going to look at the end. And then the
tickets is the description of how we're
going to get there. Okay, we can see
it's been written and published to the
issue tracker. If I open this up, we can
see it is in here. So, it's very nice
and detailed. It's got a problem
statement, a solution, a bunch of user
stories, implementation decisions,
testing decisions, a lot of stuff here.
And this is going to be really useful
cuz we'll be able to compare this at the
end to make sure that our implementation
matched the spec. So, now that we've got
the spec, I'm going to go into the same
session, not going to change sessions
here, and now I'm going to say to
tickets. And this is where it will
basically try to turn the spec into an
implementation plan. Each one of these
tickets is supposed to just be the size
of a single context window or a single
smart zone. And if we look here, we can
see that it's kind of given us three
tickets here. So, three slices. I think
that these three slices are a little bit
much. I actually think it can be done in
one slice. Do it in one slice instead.
And so it's now put this in a file. So,
it's put the ticket in tickets.md. Now,
this is quite a bad example cuz it's
kind of copying the stuff that's in our
product requirements documents. So, let
me show you an actual real example. Here
is a spec that I implemented a couple of
days ago to remove a bunch of stuff from
a repo. So, I'm on a real removal spree
recently. And you can see that this is
the spec and underneath it has 11 sub
issues. So, 11 tickets underneath it.
And each of these tickets, so this is a
very detailed spec, each of these
tickets is a single context window
session. So, if we click into here, we
can see it's just pretty short. Most of
the acceptance criteria is already in
the main spec, and so this one is just
literally what do you build in this
session? So, that's number session one,
then session two, then session three.
You can see that how this breaks down a
huge chunk of work into manageable
pieces that the agent can then go and
do. However, here we are left with a
single manageable piece. So, what I'm
going to do is I'm going to clear the
context here. Now, we have everything we
need so that we can just run a bunch of
agents to tackle this problem. So, I can
clear the context, and then I'm just
going to say at tickets here, and I'm
before that I'll say
implement this. So, now because we have
the spec that decides where we're going
and the tickets that decide how we get
there, the agent has everything it needs
and we're ready to implement. Now, when
you're doing this by hand, the idea is
that you then implement each ticket one
by one. So, you don't say do every
single ticket, you say okay, we go and
implement, then we see if we've hit the
smart zone. If we haven't, maybe we can
squeeze in one more ticket here, but
usually I would say you clear in between
every single ticket. Then, once you've
done all of the implementation, you've
got your full thing all implemented,
then you can go and code review and do
the final check against the spec. We can
see here it really was a very small
piece of work actually. It's only 42
.7k, and it's now about to, as part of
the implement, run the code review. As
part of the implement script, it goes
and runs all the type check, runs the
build, run is doing even more
verification, checking AI Hero internal
help, shows only edit commits, and it's
gone and loaded the code review skill.
This review is based on two axes. First,
it compares the work done against the
original spec. This is really useful
when you've done a huge chunk of work
and the agent might have forgotten
things in tickets or the tickets might
have been unspecified. Doing a final
pass means you actually nail everything.
And then it also checks against the
standards documentation that you've got
in your own repo. In this repo we don't
really have any coding standards
documented anywhere, but if it doesn't
detect any, then it uses some classic
ones kind of from Martin Fowler. So it
looks at code smells, tries to figure
out if there's any bad stuff. Doing
these in sub agents is really important
because if you do it in the main agent,
it means that the main agent already has
written the code and agents are often
really bad at editing code or improving
code they've just written. Because
they've wrote it, so they just think,
"Okay, that's fantastic. That's fine."
Whereas if you spawn some agents, then
they're going to have a clear context
window and they're going to do a much
better job reviewing the code. Okay, we
can see that both came back. So
cross-checked every acceptance criteria
against the spec, checked everything
against the standards, and cool. We're
good to go. And it's now committed
against the current branch. Beautiful.
So that is our flow complete. We aligned
before we got started. We created some
spec and tickets in order to make sure
it worked over multiple sessions. We
then implemented it and the implement
skill itself used the code review. This
is the main flow that all of my work
runs through. And the stuff that isn't
in the main flow is stuff that I'm
experimenting with, stuff that I'm
improving, always trying to get this
loop faster, better, easier to run. And
for that, if you're interested in that,
then you should check out my newsletter
for these skills. This YouTube channel
is a great place to be for subscribing
to understanding more about the skills,
but really the good stuff is on the
newsletter. If you want on the day
updates when I ship new skills, when I
add updates to
kind of that you need to keep updated
with, then this is the place to be. But
thank you so much for watching.
Hopefully this tutorial gives you an
idea on how to get set up with the
skills and what the main flow is
supposed to be. Thanks for watching,
happy skilling, and I will see you very
soon.